Vic Shan-Ho **Yang**

(949)-344-6309. Irvine, CA United States

vrootic@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/vic-yang

OBJECTIVE

Seeking an opportunity where I can utilize my 4+ years of web development in Python/Django and Android mobile development experience for both startup and enterprises.

Web Backend Dev — (Python/Flask, Django), (Ruby/Ruby on Rails), (Node.js/Express)

Web Front-end Dev — HTML, CSS(Sass), JavaScript, ReactJS, AngularJS

Mobile-Dev — Android Development (Native/Hybrid)

Fundamentals — Version Control (Git, SVN), Software Engineering (Agile), Pip, Virtualenv, Npm

WORK EXPERIENCE

MSC Software Corp., Newport Beach, California

4/2017 - present

Software Developer Intern

- Helped Apex product team to plan the whole system pipeline such as data preprocessing, data schema, database design, data stream, and an architecture of system which can support them for 2 years
- Delivered a document listed the detail requirements of the system
- Made a presentation in front of six managers to start a process of developing new monitoring tool
- Built minimum viable product to let management level understand the idea of Apex usage monitoring system
- Implemented Apex usage monitoring platform with Python/Django/PostgresSQL

National Conscription Agency Ministry of the Interior, Nantou, Taiwan **Software Developer**

5/2015 - 4/2016

- Developed salary auditing system with **Django** on Windows to boost the salary auditing processes
- Maintained a running system by adding more unit testing and backup processes.
- Built Excel file comparison program with **Electron/ReactJS**. (https://github.com/vrootic/FileCompare)

Zoaks Co. Ltd, Taipei, Taiwan

9/2013 - 9/2014

Software Developer

- Built a reader app for GOODTV Magazine on Android (4.6 stars, 1000+ downloads)
- Designed a web system for uploading PDF's and establishing index of magazine
- Programmed auto-deploying system for both iOS and Android app similar to TestFlight
- Discussed with clients in order to minimize the gap between requirements and implementation

Trend Micro Inc., Taipei, Taiwan

7/2013 - 8/2013

Software Developer Intern

- Developed new web UI for a product SafeSync with Ruby on Rails and AngularJS
- Participated in weekly Perl language and MySQL database training

IBM Corp., Taipei, Taiwan

7/2012 - 6/2013

Software Developer Intern

- Provided push notification solution for Worklight by IBM (Built a bot for booking meeting room.)
- Developed an integrated layer between Android native system and WebView for MQTT
- Won the internal backend system competition, selected as one of the most scalable system inside IBM

EDUCATION

ι	niversity	of	Cali	ifornia,	Irvine,	Irvine,	California
---	-----------	----	------	----------	---------	---------	------------

Accelerated Certificate Program, Data Science & Predictive Analytics	Mar. 2017
Accelerated Certificate Program, Business Administration	Dec. 2016

National Taiwan Normal University, Taipei, Taiwan

Master Degree, Computer Science	Feb. 2015
Bachelor Degree, Computer Science	Jun. 2012

PUBLICATIONS & AWARDS

IEEE CCNC

2016 Co-authored article on *Indoor localization using FM and DVB-T signals*

ACM-ICPC Asia Regional Contest, Hsinchu & Kaohisung, Taiwan

Sixteen Place (the 16th out of 50+ teams) 2011 2010 Honorable Mention